So I'd like to take my students onto a little journey to Stanford and show them
スタンフォードへの小さな旅に生徒を連れて行き
our self-driving car that uses sensors to sense the environment.
センサーを使って環境を感知する自動運転車を見せようと考えています
So let me dive into the class very much right now.
今からクラスに飛び込みますね
So here you can see the Google self-driving car using a road map,
ロードマップを使ってGoogleの自動運転車を確認できます
localizing itself, but in
それ自体をローカライズしていますが
addition what's shown here in red are measurements of other vehicles.
赤で示されているのは他の車の測定です
The car uses lasers and radars to track other vehicles.
車はレーザーとレーダーを使って他の車を追跡します
And today, we're going to talk about how to find other cars.
今日は 他の車を検知する方法についてお話しします
The reason why we'd like to find
他の車を検出したい理由は
other cars is because you wouldn't want to run into them.
衝突したくないからです
So we have to understand how to interpret
そのため ローカライゼーションの場合のように
sensor data to make assessments not just where these other cars are,
他の自動車の位置だけでなく
as in the localization case,
その速度を評価するためにセンサーデータを解釈する方法を
but also how fast they're moving.
理解する必要があります
So if you can drive in a way that avoids collisions with them in the future,
将来的に他の車両との衝突を回避する運転が可能になった場合
it's important not just for cars and for pedestrians and for bicyclists,
それは車両だけでなく歩行者や自転車にとっても重要なことです
and understanding where the cars are and making predictions where they're going to
また 車両の位置を把握し その移動先を予測することは
move is absolutely essential for safe driving in the Google car project.
Googleの自動車プロジェクトで安全運転を実現するために絶対に不可欠です
So in this class we will talk about tracking,
このクラスではトラッキングについて説明し
and the technique I like to teach you is called a Kalman Filter.
カルマンフィルターという手法を紹介します
This is an insanely popular technique for estimating the state of a system.
これは システムの状態を推定するための非常に人気のある手法です
Kalman Filters estimate a continuous state.
カルマンフィルターは連続した状態を推定します
And as a result,
その結果 カルマンフィルターは単峰性の分布を提供します
the Kalman Filter happens to give us a uni-modal distribution,
これがどのようなものなのか
and I'll tell you in a second what that means.
この後説明します
Let me start with an example.
まずは例から始めましょう
Consider the car down here.
ここに車があるとします
Let's assume it senses this measurement: an object here,
それがこの測定を感知すると仮定しましょうオブジェクトはここ
here, here, and here at the times t equals 0,
ここ ここ そしてここにあり それぞれ時刻を表すtは0
t equals 1, 2 and 3.
1 2 3です
Where would you assume the object would be at t equals four?
オブジェクトがt=4になるのはどこでしょうか?
Check one of those three boxes.
該当するボックスをチェックしてください